Daniel Carter Beard Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Daniel Carter Beard Papers 1798-1941 1931-1935
MSS12161
Beard, Daniel Carter, 1850-1941
72,000 items
261 containers plus 2 oversize
105 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Artist, author, editor, and cofounder of the Boy Scouts of America. Correspondence, diaries, family papers, speeches, articles, collected source material for writings and speeches, school composition books, address books, sketch books, illustrations, photographs, memorabilia, and printed matter relating chiefly to Beard's activities at the Culver Military Academy, Dan Beard Outdoor School, and with the Boy Scouts of America.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Baden-Powell of Gilwell, Robert Stephenson Smyth Baden-Powell, Baron, 1857-1941--Correspondence.; Beard family--Correspondence.; Beard family.; Beard, Daniel Carter, 1850-1941.; Beard, Daniel Carter, 1850-1941. Hardly a man Is now alive; the autobiography of Dan Beard. 1939.; Beard, Frank, 1842-1905. Frank Beard papers.; Beard, James Henry, 1812-1893. James Henry Beard papers.; Borglum, Gutzon, 1867-1941--Correspondence.; Browne, Belmore, 1880-1954--Correspondence.; Christy, Howard Chandler, 1873-1952--Correspondence.; Clemens, Samuel Langhorne, 1835-1910--Correspondence.; Fisher, George J., -1960--Correspondence.; Garland, Hamlin, 1860-1940--Correspondence.; Gibson, Charles Dana, 1867-1944--Correspondence.; Grey, Zane, 1872-1939--Correspondence.; Head, Walter W.--Correspondence.; Howells, William Dean, 1837-1920--Correspondence.; Markham, Edwin, 1852-1940--Correspondence.; Martin, Edward Sandford, 1856-1939--Correspondence.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956--Correspondence.; Paine, Albert Bigelow, 1861-1937--Correspondence.; Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts), 1884-1947--Correspondence.; Pinchot, Gifford, 1865-1946--Correspondence.; Pitz, Henry C. (Henry Clarence), 1895-1976--Correspondence.; Post, Augustus, 1873-1952--Correspondence.; Pratt, George D. (George Dupont), 1869-1935--Correspondence.; Presbrey, Frank, 1855-1936--Correspondence.; Remington, Frederic, 1861-1909--Correspondence.; Rockwell, Norman, 1894-1978--Correspondence.; Roosevelt family--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Edith Kermit Carow, 1861-1948--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Franklin D. (Franklin Delano), 1882-1945--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1858-1919--Correspondence.; Roosevelt, Theodore, 1887-1944--Correspondence.; Seton, Ernest Thompson, 1860-1946--Correspondence.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968--Correspondence.; Steele, Frederic Dorr, 1873-1944--Correspondence.; Stone, A. J. (Andrew Jackson), 1859-1918--Correspondence.; Taft, Lorado, 1860-1936--Correspondence.; Van Loon, Hendrik Willem, 1882-1944--Correspondence.; Vreeland, Frederick K. (Frederick King), 1874- --Correspondence.; Ward, John Quincy Adams, 1830-1910--Correspondence.; West, James E. (James Edward), 1876-1948--Correspondence.; Wister, Owen, 1860-1938--Correspondence.; Woolf, S. J. (Samuel Johnson), 1880-1948--Correspondence.; Wyeth, N. C. (Newell Convers), 1882-1945--Correspondence.
Organizations
Boy Scouts of America.; Charles Scribner's Sons--Correspondence.; Culver Military Academy.; Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys (Pike County, Pa.); J.B. Lippincott Company--Correspondence.; Sons of Daniel Boone.
Subjects
Boy Scouts--Periodicals.; Boy Scouts--United States.; Boys--United States--Societies and clubs.; Camps--Pennsylvania--Pike County.; Military education--United States.; Private schools--Indiana--Culver.; Youth--United States--Societies, etc.
Titles
Boys' life--Correspondence.; Boys' life.
Occupations
Artists.; Authors.; Boy Scout leaders.; Editors.
Acquisition Information
The papers of Daniel Carter Beard, artist, author, editor and cofounder of the Boy Scouts of America, were given to the Library of Congress by his estate in 1941.
Transfers
Pictorial items including paintings, watercolors, drawings, and photographs have been transferred to the Library's Prints and Photographs Division where they are identified as part of these papers. An inventory of this material is available in their finding aid.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Daniel Carter Beard are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Biographical Note
Date Event
1850, 21 June Born, Cincinnati, Ohio
1880 1884 Student, Art Students League, New York, N.Y.
1882 Published What To Do and How To Do It. The American Boys Handy Book. New York: C. Scribner's Sons
1889 Illustrated first edition of Mark Twain's Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court
1893 1900 Taught, New York School of Applied Design for Woman, New York, N.Y.
1894 Married Beatrice Alice Jackson
1905 Founded Sons of Daniel Boone
1905 1906 Editor, Recreation magazine
1910 Cofounder, Boy Scouts of America
1910 1941 National scout commissioner and member of the executive board, Boy Scouts of America
1911 1915 Organized and directed Department of Woodcraft, Culver Military Academy, Culver, Ind.
1915 Established Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys
1939 Published Hardly a Man Is Now Alive. New York: Doubleday, Doran
1941, 11 June Died, Suffern, N.Y.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Daniel Carter Beard (1850-1941) span the years 1798-1941, with the bulk of the material dated between 1915 and 1935. The collection consists of correspondence, diaries, family papers, speeches, articles, collected source material for writings and speeches, school composition books, address books, sketch books, illustrations, photographs, memorabilia, and printed matter relating to Beard's activities at the Culver Military Academy, Dan Beard Outdoor School, and with the Boy Scouts of America. The papers are organized into nine series: Diaries; Family Correspondence; Family Papers; General Correspondence; Special Correspondence; Subject File; Speech, Article, and Book File; Miscellany; and Oversize.
The three major phases of Beard's career as illustrator, author, and guiding spirit of the American Boy Scout movement are amply documented. Items relating to his life as an artist include numerous early sketch books and composition books containing essays and lessons prepared during his student years. Beard furnished pictures for the first illustrated editions of Samuel Langhorne Clemens's Connecticut Yankee in King Arthur's Court and Tom Sawyer Abroad, and the papers contain his correspondence with Clemens concerning this work. There is a great deal of correspondence with Charles Dana Gibson, who served as best man at Beard's wedding. Correspondents from the art world include Gutzon Borglum, Howard Chandler Christy, Henry C. Pitz, Frederic Remington, Norman Rockwell, Frederic Dorr Steele, Lorado Taft, John Quincy Adams Ward, S. J. Woolf, and N. C. Wyeth.
Daniel Beard came from an artistic background. His father, James Henry Beard, was a well-known portrait painter among whose sitters were Henry Clay, John Quincy Adams, and Benjamin Harrison. His brother, Frank Beard, originated the once popular "chalk talks," which were lectures illustrated by the speaker with crayon sketches drawn during the course of the lecture. The Family Correspondence and Family Papers series in these papers contain many manuscripts of both Frank Beard and James Henry Beard, including a draft of the latter's autobiography.
Daniel Beard's career as an author is represented with the original manuscript of his autobiography, Hardly a Man Is Now Alive (1939), and an extensive collection of articles devoted to outdoor life that range in subject matter from the making of "Billy Bow-Leg Moccasins" to instructions for tying a "Real Sour-Dough Diamond Hitch." Most of the articles were prepared for publication in the magazine Boy's Life, to which Beard was a regular monthly contributor. There is also a great deal of correspondence with the publishing firms of J. B. Lippincott Company and Charles Scribner's Sons, which printed most of the twenty-seven books written by Beard. Among his correspondents in the field of literature are Samuel Langhorne Clemens, Hamlin Garland, Zane Grey, William Dean Howells, Edwin Markham, H. L. Mencken, Albert Bigelow Paine, Maxwell Perkins, Upton Sinclair, Hendrik Willem Van Loon, and Owen Wister.
The third and most bountiful phase of the collection concerns Beard's efforts to create and develop the Boy Scout movement in the United States. There are papers relating to Sons of Daniel Boone (renamed Boy Pioneers of America), the organization Beard established in 1905 that was a forerunner of the Boy Scouts of America. In addition to the manuscripts detailing the origin of the Boy Scouts in 1910, there is important correspondence with other leaders of the scouting movement in this country and abroad. Perhaps the most important of these are with Robert Stephenson Smyth Baden-Powell, Baron Baden-Powell of Gilwell, the British soldier who was the founder of the original Boy Scout movement in 1908; and Ernest Thompson Seton, author of the nature study Wild Animals I Have Known and organizer of yet another woodlore group, the Woodcraft Indians (1902). Among the major figures initially associated with the Boy Scout organization who are represented in these papers are George J. Fisher, Walter W. Head, Edward Sanford Martin, Augustus Post, George D. Pratt, Frank Presbrey, Isaac Sutton, Frederick Vreeland, and James E. West.
President Theodore Roosevelt's dictum regarding the strenuous life strongly appealed to Daniel Beard, and following the president's death he instituted annual pilgrimages to his grave at Oyster Bay, Long Island. The papers contain Beard's correspondence with Roosevelt, his widow, Edith Kermit Carow Roosevelt, son Theodore Roosevelt, Jr. (1887-1944), and other members of the family.
There are three groups of Special Correspondence relating to the Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys, the Boy Scouts, and the Sons of Daniel Boone. The latter two groups consist of letters received by Beard from children who were members of these organizations. The correspondence relating to the Dan Beard Outdoor School for Boys concerns the summer camp he established in 1915 at Hawley, Pennsylvania, and operated until the mid-1930s. The letters are inquiries from parents concerning the camp and the progress of their children and purely internal correspondence relating to the financial and logistical operations of the camp.
Arrangement of the Papers
The collection is arranged in nine series:
Diaries, 1875-1900
Family Correspondence, 1814-1938
Family Papers, circa 1798-1933
General Correspondence, circa 1865-1941
Special Correspondence, 1915-1940
Subject File
Speech, Article, and Book File, 1890-1940
Miscellany
Oversize
Container List
- Diaries, 1875-1900 (Box 1)
  Diaries.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1875-1900, undated (Box 1)
- Family Correspondence, 1814-1938 (Box 2-7)
  Family letters sent and received.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of family member and therein by name of correspondent.
  - Bartlett, Rowena (Box 2)
    - Cox, Flovita, and Julia E. C. Robinson
  - Beard, Adelia
    - Beard, Alice
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, Thomas Carter
    - "F-V" miscellaneous
  - Beard, Alice
    - Beard, Barbara
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, Lina
    - Family
    - "A-V" miscellaneous
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Barbara
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, James Carter (grandfather)
    - Beard, James Carter (uncle)
    - Cleaver, Robert S.
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Beatrice A.
    - Walford & Co. and Woman's Club of Suffern, N.Y.
  - Beard, Betty
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
  - Beard, Caroline
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, Dedie
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, James Carter
    - Beard, James H.
    - Beard, Lina
    - Carter, Adelia
    - Carter, Tom
    - Diamond, J. M.
    - Disney, Caroline
    - Disney, Cornelia
    - Neville, C. M.
    - Ramping, Cornelia
    - Ware, Angie
    - With unidentified
  - Beard, Daniel Bartlett
    - Beard, Lina
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Daniel Carter (Box 3)
    - Beard, Alice (niece)
    - Beard, Alice (wife)
    - Beard, Annie R.
    - Beard, Augustus F.
    - Beard, Barbara
    - Beard, Betty
    - Beard, Carrie
    - Beard, Chester Fellows
    - Beard, Daniel (nephew)
    - Beard, Daniel Bartlett
    - Beard, Dedie
    - Beard, Douglas and Roger
    - Beard, Edward Chester (Box 4)
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, George H.
    - Beard, Gladys
    - Beard, Harry
    - Beard, James H. (father)
    - Beard, James H. (Jamie, nephew)
    - Beard, Laura
  - Beard, Lina (Box 5)
    - Beard, Mary
    - Beard, Morris
    - Beard, Nellie
    - Beard, Wheeler
    - Beard, William C.
    - Beard, Mrs. William C.
    - Beard, William S.
    - Blair, Etta
    - Blair, Florence
    - Blair, Katherine
    - Callahan, Mrs. J. S. Neville
    - Carter, Daniel B.
    - Carter, Jessie B.
    - Carter, Mary L.
    - Carter, Thomas
    - Carter, Thomas P.
    - Champian, Belle
    - Cox, S. B.
    - Densmore, Florence
    - Densmore, Margaretta
    - Freehan, Maude Hamilton
    - Jackman, Violette Rhodes
    - Kendall, Cora Carter
    - Loupy, Louise M.
    - Moore, Frances C.
    - Wingate, Carl
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Edward
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, James Carter
    - Beard, Nellie
    - Rosecrans, William S.
    - Rosseau, L. H.
  - Beard, Harry (Box 6)
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, Dedie
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, James Carter
    - Beard, James H.
    - Beard, Jimey
    - Beard, Lina and Dedie
    - A-W miscellaneous
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, James Carter
    - Howe, J. F.
    - Grandmother
  - Beard, James Henry
    - Beard, Caroline
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, Harriet
    - Beard, Harry
    - Beard, Harry W.
    - Beard, James Carter
    - Carter, Thomas P.
    - Hayes, Rutherford B.
    - Sherman, William T.
    - Spofford, Ainsworth Rand
    - A-W miscellaneous (Box 7)
  - Beard, Lina
    - Beard, Alice
    - Beard, Barbara
    - Beard, Carrie
    - Beard, Daniel Carter
    - Beard, Dedie
    - Beard, Frank
    - Beard, Gladys
    - Beard, James
    - Beard, James H.
    - Carter, James B.
    - Scribner, Arthur H.
    - A-W miscelleous
    - Unidentified
  - Beard, Morris
    - Wack, Henry Wellington
  - Beard, Nellie
    - Berad, Frank
    - Beard, Lina
    - D, T miscellaneous
  - Beard, Thomas
    - Beard, James H.
  - Beard, William H.
    - Beard, Frank
  - Carter, Deborah
    - Denison, William
  - Denison, Pollie C.
    - Carter, Thomas P.
  - Unidentified
- Family Papers, circa 1798-1933 (Box 8-18)
  Writings, drawings and sketches, diaries, biographical papers, financial material, military papers, photographs, printed matter, and miscellany.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of family member and therein by type of material.
  - Beard, Adelia (Box 8)
    - Miscellany
    - Printed matter
  - Beard, Alice
    - Article
    - Biographical papers
    - Diary
  - Beard, Daniel Bartlett
    - Writing
  - Beard, Frank
    - Articles
    - Biographical papers
    - Chalk talks
    - Obituaries (Box 9)
    - Original drawings
    - Photographs
    - Printed matter
    - Writings
    - Writings (Box 10)
  - Beard, Harry
    - Debate
    - Diaries
    - Financial papers
    - Military papers
    - Military papers (Box 11)
    - Military papers (Box 12)
    - Drawings See Oversize (Box 12A)
    - Sketch book
    - Stories
    - Miscellany (Box 13)
    - Miscellany (Box 14)
    - Photographs
    - Printed matter
  - Beard, James H. (Box 15)
    - Autobiography
    - Biographical papers (Box 16)
    - Engraving
    - Financial papers
    - Miscellany
    - Printed matter
  - Beard, Lina (Box 17)
    - Biographical papers
    - Miscellany
    - Obituaries
  - Beard, Nellie
    - Miscellany
  - Beard, William H.
    - Address
  - Carter, Thomas (family)
    - Miscellany
  - Miscellany
    - Calling cards
    - Copper plates
    - Drawings
    - General
    - General (Box 18)
    - Photographs
    - Printed matter
- General Correspondence, circa 1865-1941 (Box 19-147)
  Letters sent and received.
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - Abbott, Lyman (Box 19)
  - Abercrombie, David
  - Abercrombie & Fitch Co.
  - Adams, James Truslow
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins
  - Adler, Cyrus
  - Adler, Felix
  - Aldine Club
  - Alexander, William V.
  - Alford, Floyd
  - Allen, George E.
  - Allen, Mary Jester
  - Alpaugh, H. R.
  - American Blue Book Publishers (Box 20)
  - American Book Co.
  - American Boy
  - American Forestry Association
  - American Indian, Museum
  - American Lithographic Co.
  - American Museum of Natural History
  - American School of the Air
  - Anderson, Algernon A. (Box 21)
  - Anderson, Mary See Container 51, Fuller, G.
  - Andrews, Roy Chapman
  - Angell, James Rowland
  - Appleton (D.) & Co.
  - Arts and Sciences, Society of
  - Ashley, William B. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Atkinson, Will (Box 22)
  - Aures, Victor
  - Authors Club
  - Author's League of America
  - "A-Alw" miscellaneous
  - "Ama-Ay" miscellaneous (Box 23)
  - Bacheller, Irving (Box 24)
  - Baden-Powell, Robert Stephenson Smyth
  - Baird, Spencer F.
  - Bakeless, John
  - Baker, Newton Diehl
  - Barclay, Lorne W.
  - Barrett, Daisy
  - Barton, Bruce
  - Beach, William N. See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Beard, Charles A.
  - Beckman, Earl W.
  - Beebe, William
  - Belknap, Reginald
  - Bell, J.
  - Benson, Oscar H.
  - Bernhardt, Carl
  - Bierstadt, Albert (Box 25)
  - Big Brother Movement
  - Bigelow, Edward F.
  - Bigelow, Pultney
  - Bigelow, W. F.
  - Birchard (C. C.) & Co.
  - Bispham, Charles P.
  - Blackman Co.
  - Blanchard, Lina R.
  - Boardman, John R.
  - Bogan, Samuel
  - Bogart, William S. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Bogert, Henry L.
  - Bogert, Marston T.
  - Bok, Edward
  - Bok, William J.
  - Bolton, Theodore
  - Booth, Edwin See Container 51, Fuller, G.
  - Booth, Evangeline
  - Borglum, Gutzon
  - Boswell, M. G.
  - Bowes, Major Edward
  - Boy Scouts of America Correspondents include
    - Baden-Powell, Robert Stephenson Smyth
    - Fisher, George J.
    - Head, Walter W.
    - Martin, Edward Sanford
    - Post, Augustus
    - Pratt, George D.
    - Presbrey, Frank
    - Seton, Ernest Thompson
    - Sutton, Isaac
    - Vreeland, Frederick K.
    - West, James E.
  - Boyer, James R.
  - Boys' Life Correspondents include (Box 26)
    - Ashley, William B.
    - Carroll, V. E.
    - Cave, Edward
    - Clymer, H. M.
    - Coffin, B. P.
    - Colver, Frederic L.
    - Crampton, C. Ward
    - Crump, Irving
    - Daniels, Hawthorne
    - Demorest, William
    - Green Bar Bill
    - Mathiews, Franklin K.
    - Mathiews, Norman T.
    - O'Connor, Evelyn
    - O'Connor, Evelyn (Box 27)
    - Patten, F. J.
    - Rigney, Francis J.
    - Stearns, Myron M.
    - Willson, Paul W.
  - Boys Magazine
  - Brainard, David Legge
  - Branch, Les
  - Brandt, Albert
  - Brant, Irving
  - Breckinridge, Curry Desha
  - Brinton, J. H.
  - Brisbane, Arthur
  - Brockway, James E.
  - Brooks, Emerson
  - Books, Harlow
  - Broome, Bertram
  - Brown, Curtis
  - Brown, Ethel Zaring
  - Brown, James H.
  - Brown, James R.
  - Brown, K. L.
  - Brown, Lathrop
  - Browne, Belmore (Box 28)
  - Brundage, W.
  - Bryan, William Jennings
  - Buchanan, Louis L.
  - Buchanan, S. Edwin
  - Buck, Frank
  - Bucknam, A. J.
  - Bull, Arthur
  - Bull, Charles Livingston
  - Bull, Mrs. Charles Livingston
  - Bull, George R.
  - Burdett, John L.
  - Burdick, Frederick E.
  - Burleigh, George W.
  - Burnham, John B.
  - Burroughs, John
  - Burroughs (John) Association
  - Burton, Harold
  - Butler, George M.
  - Butler, Nicholas Murray
  - Butler, Pierce
  - Butler, William Mill
  - Butler, Ovid
  - Butler, Ellis Parker
  - Byrd, Richard E.
  - "B-By" miscellaneous (Box 29-32)
  - Cadmus Book Shop (Box 33)
  - Camp Directors Association
  - Camp-Fire Club Correspondents include
    - Beach, William N.
    - Bogart, William S.
    - Coffin, William Edward
    - Couzens, John C.
    - Frazer, John F.
    - Greeley, William B.
    - Hoisington, Fred
    - Jelliffe, W. R.
    - Möller, J. A. L.
    - Pratt, George Dupont
    - Rice, Arthur F.
    - Seymour, Edmund
    - Spence, Bernard L.
    - Syms, Parker
  - Camp Fire Girls
  - Carmichael, Leonard
  - Carroll, V. E. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Carter, Boake
  - Cave, Edward See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Century Association
  - Century Publications
  - Century Syndicate
  - Chabrun, Jacques
  - Chapman, Charles S.
  - Chapman, Frank M.
  - Charles Scribner's Sons (Box 34)
  - Chase, Linwood
  - Christian Science Monitor
  - Christy, Howard Chandler
  - Circle Magazine
  - Clark, Agnes Elizabeth
  - Clark (Arthur H.) Co.
  - Clark, James L.
  - Clarke, James M.
  - Clay, Cassius
  - Clemens, Cyril (Box 35)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne For additional information see Container 50, Force, C. W.
  - Clymer, H. M. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Cleveland, Grover
  - Cobb, F. C.
  - Cody, William
  - Coffin, B. P. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Coffin, William Edward See also Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Coit, James O.
  - Cleaver, Robert S.
  - Collier, Barron G.
  - Collier's
  - Columbia Broadcasting System
  - Colver, Frederic L. See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Combs, Reese (Box 36)
  - Conant, James B.
  - Conlon, Ernest L.
  - Connolly, Maurice E.
  - Coogan, Jackie
  - Cooke, Frederick N.
  - Coolidge, Calvin
  - Copeland, Royal S.
  - Cornucopia Lodge
  - Cornwell & Stevens
  - Cortissoz, Royal
  - Cosmopolitan
  - Cotting, C. E.
  - Country Gentleman
  - Couzens, John F. See Container 33, Camp-Fire Club
  - Covey, Frank Howard
  - Crampton, C. Ward. See Container 26, Boys' Life (Box 37)
  - Crawford, Jack
  - Crosby, Richard T.
  - Crowell, Robert L.
  - Crowell (Thomas Y.) Co.
  - Crowninshield, Frank
  - Crump, Irving See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Crump, Walter
  - Culver Military Academy
  - Curtis, Anna L.
  - Curtis, Carlton C.
  - Curtis, Cyrus H. K.
  - Custer, Elizabeth
  - "C-Can" miscellaneous
  - "Cap-Cy" miscellaneous (Box 38-40)
  - Daniel Boone Memorial (Box 41)
  - Daniels, Hawthorne See also Container 26, Boys' Life
  - Dannenberg, Arthur
  - Darlington, George A.
  - Darrell, Alfred W.
  - Dartmouth College
  - Dauber & Pine Bookshops
  - Davenport, Homer
  - Davey, George Sennett
  - Davidson, Frank E.
  - Davie, Fred G.
  - Davis, Elmer
  - Davis, Milton F. See also Container 92, New York Military Academy
  - Davis and Sanford
  - Dawley, George A.
  - Dawson, Benjamin B.
  - DeGraffenried, Thomas P.
  - Delaware, Mme. A.
  - deMille, Anna George
  - Deming, Edwin Willard
  - Demorest, William See Container 26, Boys' Life
  - deSherbinin, Michael J.
  - Dewey, George (Box 42)
  - Dewey, Thomas E.
  - Dickerson, John S.
  - Diehl, Karl F.
  - Digges, William J.
  - Dimitrieff, Nickolai V.
  - Dimock, Anthony W.
  - Dix, John A.
  - Dixon, Benjamin S.
  - Doan, John K.
  - Dodd, Edward B.
  - Dodd, Edward H.
  - Dodge, Henry
  - Dodge, Wendell Phillips
  - Doubleday, Russell
  - Doubleday, Doran & Co.
  - Doubleday, Page & Co.
  - Douglas, Archibald
  - Douglas, Henry S.
  - DuPont, Eugene
  - Durieux, A. H.
  - Dutton (E. P.) & Co.
  - "D-Dam" miscellaneous
  - "Dan-Dy" miscellaneous (Box 43-44)
  - Earhart, Amelia (Box 45)
  - Early, Stephen
  - East River Savings Bank
  - Eddy, H. Laurance
  - Edison, Thomas A.
  - Edson, Carroll A.
  - Ehler, George W.
  - Eisner, J. Lester
  - Elliott, Margaret R.
  - Ellis, Griffith O.
  - Emery, F. J.
  - Emerson, Joe
  - Encyclopaedia Britannica